RÉSUMÉ

Peter Lam

12 Christine Crescent REDBANK PLAINS OLD 4301

Home: (07) 3814 0478 Mobile: 0466 107 677

Email: peter_hclam@yahoo.com.au

Introduction

Career Objective

An experienced professional of 23 years, I have learned the intricate skill of working and communicating with different groups of people in various capacity and environment. My greatest motivation is to be able to add value to people, helping them to resolve whatever issues they may be facing. I bring to any organization a strong energy and drive for success and I hope to continue to use my strong analytical and organisational skills in my future endeavor.

Key Strengths

- ✓ Diligent and responsible; never quit until end result is achieved
- ✓ Strong planning, organisational and time management skills
- ✓ Ability to break down complex issue into smaller manageable tasks
- ✓ Willing to take risk and think outside the box
- ✓ Strong adherent to policies and procedures; however, willing to use different approaches to problem solving
- ✓ Highly adaptable to changes and quick to adapt to new environment; learn new skills quickly while on the job
- ✓ Ability to communicate at all levels (end users, programmers, system administrators, Directors/senior managers, vendors and government agencies), including training and skills transfer
- ✓ Strong people management skills; able to motivate subordinates and develop their potential
- ✓ Experienced in logistic support and services

Personality

A strong analytical thinker, I am highly motivated in solving problems and persevere until I achieve the end results. I am willing to take on new challenges and I adapt quickly. A diligent and responsible person, I give credit to my subordinates for a job well done while I am quick to take responsibilities on all matters under my charge. I have the confidence of working independently, but I am also a team player. I work and communicate well with all levels, from senior management to end-users. I enjoy many sports, played competitive games in a few of them. Having embarked on a personal growth plan, I continue to improve myself through the reading of leadership and communication books. I relax by working on jigsaw puzzles.

Education/Qualifications

Bachelor of Engineering

Electrical & Electronic Engineering (Computer Option) National University of Singapore 1990

HLTAID003 Provide First Aid (includes HLTAID001 & HLTAID002)

CBD College

2014

TAE40110 Certificate IV in Training And Assessment

Bremer Institute of TAFE 2014

Career Summary

Dates	Employers	Positions
Feb 2013 – present	Self Employed	 Coach, Teacher and Speaker
Jan 2006 – Sep 2013	Herron Todd White Australia	 Software Developer
May 2004 – Dec 2005	Connell Wagner Pty Ltd	 Senior IT Officer
Oct 2003 – May 2004	Stylus Pty Ltd	• Storeman
Apr 2001 – Feb 2003	Lim & Tan Securities	 Information Technology Manager
Jun 2000 – Apr 2001	Inquisitive Mind	 Senior Quality Engineer
Sep 1993 – Jun 2000	Lotus Development	 Technology Consultant Senior Lotus Notes Developer Senior Software Engineer
Jun 1990 – Sep 1993	CSA Research	Software Engineer

Professional Development

• An Independent Certified Coach, Teacher and Speaker

The John Maxwell Team 2013-2014

HLTAID003 Provide First Aid (includes HLTAID001 & HLTAID002)

CBD College 2014

TAE40110 – Certificate IV in Training and Assessment

Bremer Institute of TAFE 2014

30772QLD – Certificate IV in Christian Ministry and Theology

Hope College 2011

• 30215QLD - Course in General Safety Induction

B & I Safety Pty Ltd 2005

Skills/Experience

Key: TY= Total Years Used; LU = When Last Used; EL = Experience Level

(Scale: Advanced, Good, Fair, Some)

Skill Area	TY	LU	EL	Skill Area	TY	LU	EL
Hardware:				Server:			
IBM PC Systems	23	Current	Advanced	Lotus Domino Server	17	Current	Advanced
Operating System	1:			Office Applications:			
Windows XP	10	Current	Good	Microsoft Word	10	Current	Advanced
				Microsoft Excel	10	Current	Advanced
Programming Languages:			Microsoft PowerPoint	10	Current	Good	
Lotus Notes	17	Current	Advanced				
Visual Basic	7	Current	Advanced	Web Browser Applications:			
HTML	7	Current	Good	Internet Explorer	17	Current	Advanced
Java	3	Current	Some	Mozilla Firefox	3	Current	Advanced
				Google Chrome	2	Current	Advanced

Previous Position

Software Developer Herron Todd White Australia

Jan 2005 - Sep 2013

Herron Todd White is the largest independent property valuation and advisory group in Australia. She has offices established in many parts of Australia, providing a comprehensive range of valuation, research and advisory services which are used by financial institutions, solicitors, accountants, property developers and corporations. The IT Department in Brisbane provides IT service and support to the whole organisation across the country. As the Software Developer reporting to the IT Manager, I am responsible for the development and maintenance of the current job management system, including level 2 and 3 helpdesk support.

Kev Achievements

- ✓ Developed application that allowed valuers to capture information out in the field.
- ✓ Developed web services interface using LIXI schema.
- ✓ Improved efficiency by allowing valuers to email photos from their mobile devices to job management system.
- ✓ Maintained existing MS Word report templates using visual basic script.
- \checkmark Developed web services interface with SMS provider to send out SMS messages.

Senior Information Technology Officer Connell Wagner Pty Ltd

May 2004 - Dec 2005

Connell Wagner is one of Asia Pacific's leading engineering, planning, surveying and management consultancy company. She has offices established in many parts of Australia, New Zealand and South-East Asia. The IT Department in Brisbane provides IT service and support to seven offices in Queensland. As the Senior IT Officer reporting to the Region IT Manager, I supervise three IT Officers in providing IT Help Desk support to the region. My responsibilities include Help Desk support, server backup, PABX support, and new users setup and computer allocation.

Previous Position Cont'd

Key Achievements

- ✓ Acting Region IT Manager while new manager was being recruited.
- ✓ Upgraded Lotus Notes Client from R5 to R6.
- ✓ Conducted Lotus Notes training to over 200 users.
- ✓ Conducted video conferencing trail with offices within Queensland.
- ✓ Upgraded old computers in Brisbane office.
- ✓ Set up new starters (accounts, computers, phone).
- ✓ Set up SOE images for cloning new PCs.
- ✓ Developed electronic phone directory and automated generation of phone list in Excel format.
- ✓ Automated mail-in to Helpdesk Job system.

Storeman

Stylus Pty Ltd

Oct 2003 - May 2004

Stylus is a manufacturer of bathroom equipment and accessories with a Spa manufacturing facility in Brisbane. My job is to add frame to Spa as ordered by customers. Within one month of joining the company, I was made in charged of the framing section. Besides framing, I also help out in testing and packing the Spa for shipment.

Information Technology Manager <u>Lim & Tan Securities</u>

Apr 2001 - Feb 2003

Lim & Tan Securities is a stock broking company with about 200 employees. The IT Department is responsible for all aspects of IT services and support. This includes helpdesk support, network infrastructure, web, Domino and file servers, IBM AS/400 server, firewall, hubs and routers, dumb terminals, printers, UPS, Internet Online trading system (e-business), application development, IT training, and vendor liaison. As head of the department, I report directly to the Executive Director, with 4 IT Officers reporting to me. My role is to oversee the daily operation of the department, source for new IT solutions, and manage all IT projects. This role also required me to be on standby 24x7. I am also a member of the management team that meets fortnightly.

Key Achievements

- ✓ Upgraded all photocopiers from analog to digital, thereby allowing network printing and faxing. This saved costs on laser printers and papers.
- ✓ Upgraded Domino servers from 4.x to R5 and from R5 to R6.
- ✓ Rolled out 20 Lotus Notes applications within a period of less than 2 years.
- ✓ Spearheaded the implementation of an Internet payment gateway.
- Implemented Norton Anti-virus Corporate Edition for users, Domino servers, and file servers.
- ✓ Picked up AS/400 Report Query on the job without formal training.
- Conducted IT training on Microsoft Windows, Microsoft Office, Lotus Notes, Internet browsers to end users.
- ✓ Coordinated office renovation and moving of IT equipments to new premises.
- ✓ Started Business Continuity planning and conducted yearly Disaster Recovery exercises.

While working in Lim & Tan, I was involved in their Business Process Redesign program. With the help of the Dean of School of Business Administration of a local university, we embarked on the redesign of all the business processes in the company. I had the privilege of heading a team and was also a member of another team in this program.

Previous Position Cont'd

Senior Quality Engineer Inquisitive Mind Jun 2000 - Apr 2001

Inquisitive Mind was a dot-com company that provided education portal to schools and the general public. It had branches in Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan. I joined the company to set up her Quality Control department, putting in place procedures and testing schools intranet applications. One of the major projects I managed was the deployment of the software bugs tracking system. This system was also used by the Customer Service department to log calls from customers. Another project I managed and developed was the workflow process for registration and creation of new schools. Developed using Lotus/Domino on Linux, this web-based workflow application was used across Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan. Not only does it require SSL encryption, it also need to support Chinese characters and the usual workflow email notification.

Technology Consultant Senior Lotus Notes Developer Senior Software Engineer Lotus Development Sep 1993 – Jun 2000

Lotus Development, a fully owned subsidiary of IBM, is the company that produces Lotus Notes and Lotus SmartSuite. The company in Singapore is responsible for the Asia Pacific market, including the development and localization of the products for Asia markets. I joined Lotus Development as a software engineer responsible for the development and localization of Lotus 1-2-3 for China, Korea and Taiwan. After 3 years, I moved to the Information Systems department to develop Lotus Notes applications for internal customers. This role required close working with Human Resource, Finance, Sales & Marketing, and Operations departments. Some of the applications I developed were used by our consultants for external customers. Just before I left, I was appointed a Technology Consultant, looking into emerging Lotus and IBM technologies and see how they can be used as a showcase to customers. I researched into products such as SameTime, LearningSpace, and QuickPlace.

Software Engineer <u>CSA Research</u> Jun 1990 - Sep 1993

CSA Research is a software house that developed Computer Aided Software Engineering (CASE) tools. My initial role was to develop automated testing tools to test the software applications as part of the QA process. Due to company restructuring, I was seconded to a sister company in Quebec, Canada to help develop testing tools. On returning, I was assigned the role of maintaining the computer systems and network infrastructure.

Referees

Trevor DanielsRetired Board Member Centro Church, Ipswich

I have known Trevor since 2004.

Mobile: **0411 699 742**

Mat Cantarella

IT Systems Administrator Herron Todd White Australia

Mat has been a close working colleague since 2009.

Mobile: **0407 628 829**